♪When sorrow and joy blend into ink♪
♪عندما يمتزج الحزن والفرح في الحبر♪
♪Flowers fade, rain falls, helpless as time♪
تذبل الأزهار، ويهطل المطر، عاجزين كعجز الزمن.
♪Lament this frail body, tangled in love and hate♪
♪رثوا هذا الجسد الهزيل، المتشابك بين الحب والكراهية♪
♪Yet I still wrestle with fate♪
♪ومع ذلك ما زلتُ أصارع القدر♪
♪Snow drifts down, burying all glory♪
♪ يتساقط الثلج، فيدفن كل مجد ♪
♪Blame this destiny granted to me♪
♪ألوم هذا القدر الذي مُنح لي♪
♪Trapped in the chains of love and cause♪
♪محاصرون في قيود الحب والقضية♪
♪When the dust finally settles♪
♪عندما تهدأ الأمور أخيرًا♪
=Glory in Shadows=
=المجد في الظلال=
=Episode 2= (Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org)
=الحلقة 2= (ادعموا المشرفين، شاهدوا الحلقة على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org)
(Li Manor)
(قصر لي)
Madam,
سيدتي،
here's the Li Manor.
هذا هو قصر لي.
I cannot go inside.
لا أستطيع الدخول.
If I enter, I will die for sure.
إذا دخلت، فسأموت بالتأكيد.
General Li would never let you die.
لن يسمح لك الجنرال لي بالموت أبداً.
Please, go inside.
تفضل بالدخول.
(Late Guardian General Li Jingchuan)
(الوصي الراحل الجنرال لي جينغشوان)
Halt!
وقف!
Are you Lady Yaochu?
هل أنتِ السيدة ياوتشو؟
Yes.
نعم.
I'm the Prefecture Governor's eldest daughter,
أنا الابنة الكبرى لحاكم المحافظة،
Shen Yaochu.
شن ياوتشو.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
Now that you're in the Li Manor,
الآن وقد أصبحت في قصر لي،
you only address yourself as Madam Li.
أنتِ تخاطبين نفسكِ فقط باسم السيدة لي.
And who might you be?
ومن أنت يا ترى؟
I have long served at Old Madam's side.
لقد خدمتُ إلى جانب السيدة العجوز لفترة طويلة.
You may call me Nanny Sun.
يمكنكِ مناداتي ناني صن.
So you're a servant.
إذن أنت خادم.
I'm marrying the General today,
سأتزوج الجنرال اليوم،
yet the Li family sends only a servant to greet me.
لكن عائلة لي لم ترسل سوى خادم واحد لاستقبالي.
Old Madam is unwell,
السيدة العجوز مريضة،
so she asked me to welcome you.
لذا طلبت مني أن أرحب بك.
Since you're now part of the Li family,
بما أنك أصبحت الآن جزءًا من عائلة لي،
you must abide by our household rules.
يجب عليك الالتزام بقواعد منزلنا.
You came from outside the manor,
لقد أتيت من خارج القصر،
bringing dirt.
جلب الأوساخ.
Please remove your shoes and socks
يرجى خلع حذائك وجواربك
and walk barefoot across this fire basin.
وامشِ حافي القدمين عبر حوض النار هذا.
Only then can the filth be cleansed from your body.
عندها فقط يمكن تطهير جسمك من القذارة .
Take off my shoes and walk
أخلع حذائي وأمشي
barefoot over fire?
حافي القدمين فوق النار؟
Madam, please.
سيدتي، من فضلك.
General Li sacrificed for the empire.
ضحى الجنرال لي من أجل الإمبراطورية.
Not even his remains could return home.
حتى رفاته لم تستطع العودة إلى الوطن.
Yet in the whole Li family,
لكن في عائلة لي بأكملها،
no one came for his memorial tablet.
لم يأتِ أحد لأخذ لوحته التذكارية.
You even pick on his rightful wife.
بل إنك تنتقد زوجته الشرعية أيضاً.
How is this justified?
كيف يمكن تبرير ذلك؟
Insolence!
وقاحة!
This is the custom of the family.
هذه عادة العائلة.
Then I will be insolent.
حينها سأكون وقحاً.
How can you become the lady of the Li family?
كيف يمكنكِ أن تصبحي سيدة عائلة لي؟
Yes.
نعم.
I am blunt and unruly.
أنا صريح ومتمرد.
Your Li family
عائلة لي الخاصة بكم
(Late Guardian General Li Jingchuan) might as well wed another!
(الجنرال لي جينغتشوان، الحارس الراحل) قد يتزوج من أخرى!
Guards!
حراس!
Help the new bride brush away the dust
ساعدي العروس الجديدة على إزالة الغبار
and purify her spirit with flags!
وطهّر روحها بالأعلام!
Remove her garments!
انزعي عنها ملابسها!
What's all this noise?
ما كل هذه الضوضاء؟
(Zhao Qingru Old Madam of Li Family)
(تشاو تشينغرو، السيدة القديمة لعائلة لي)
Old Madam.
السيدة العجوز.
The new bride shows no respect.
العروس الجديدة لا تُظهر أي احترام.
Her conduct is reckless.
سلوكها متهور.
I'm cleansing her as part of the ritual.
أقوم بتطهيرها كجزء من الطقوس.
You want me buried alive with a dead man?
أتريدني أن أدفن حياً مع رجل ميت؟
Keep dreaming!
استمر في الحلم!
To be buried as the rightful wife is already
أن تُدفن كزوجة شرعية هو بالفعل
a blessing for you.
نعمة لك.
The new bride, Lady Yaochu,
العروس الجديدة، السيدة ياوتشو،
was overcome with grief.
انتابه الحزن الشديد.
She struck the coffin and died,
ضربت النعش وماتت.
and was laid to rest beside my son, Jingchuan,
ودفن بجوار ابني، جينغتشوان.
in the same burial.
في نفس المدفن.
I cannot die...
لا يمكنني أن أموت...
Old Madam?
سيدتي العجوز؟
Beat her to death on the spot!
اضربها حتى الموت في الحال!
(Mother...)
(الأم...)
(Forgive me.)
(سامحني.)
(I did my best.)
(بذلت قصارى جهدي.)
Welcome the Guardian General home in triumph.
أهلاً وسهلاً بعودة رئيس مجلس الأمناء إلى الوطن منتصراً.
(Xu Shan Deputy General)
(شو شان، نائب الجنرال)
(Li Jingchuan Eldest Son of Li Family)
(لي جينغشوان، الابن الأكبر لعائلة لي)
(So he is...)
(إذن هو كذلك...)
(Li Jingchuan.)
(لي جينغ تشوان.)
You're alive?
هل أنت على قيد الحياة؟
I barely made it.
لقد نجحت بصعوبة.
Old Madam must be disappointed.
لا بد أن السيدة العجوز تشعر بخيبة أمل.
What nonsense?
أي هراء هذا؟
Seeing you alive,
رؤيتك على قيد الحياة،
nothing makes me happier.
لا شيء يسعدني أكثر من ذلك.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
General, you may hold a great rank,
أيها الجنرال، قد تكون لك رتبة عظيمة،
but before Old Madam, you're still junior.
لكن قبل السيدة العجوز، ما زلت مبتدئًا.
Why do you not dismount to greet Old Madam?
لماذا لا تنزل من على حصانك لتحية السيدة العجوز؟
Insolent servant!
خادم وقح!
You disrespect the General?
هل تُقلل من احترام الجنرال؟
Old Madam,
سيدتي العجوز،
are you saying I must kneel?
هل تقول إنه يجب عليّ أن أركع؟
Between mother and son, such formality isn't needed.
بين الأم وابنها، لا حاجة لمثل هذه الرسميات.
Yet since ancient times,
لكن منذ العصور القديمة،
it has always been ruler before kin.
لطالما كان الحاكم قبل القرابة.
By our dynasty's rites,
بحسب طقوس سلالتنا،
should it not be you, Old Madam,
ألا ينبغي أن تكوني أنتِ يا سيدتي العجوز؟
who salutes me first?
من سيحييني أولاً؟
Just joking.
أمزح فقط.
Why did you take it seriously?
لماذا أخذت الأمر على محمل الجد؟
I heard Lady Yanchu thought I had perished,
سمعت أن السيدة يانشو تعتقد أنني قد هلكت.
was grief-stricken, and wished to be buried with me.
كان حزيناً للغاية، وتمنى أن يُدفن معي.
Lady Youchu's unwavering devotion
إخلاص السيدة يوتشو الثابت
is truly touching.
إنه مؤثر حقاً.
I told you,
أخبرتك،
General Li would never let you die.
لن يسمح لك الجنرال لي بالموت أبداً.
Thank you, Old Madam, for my marriage.
شكراً لكِ يا سيدتي العجوز على زواجي.
But keeping a coffin in the courtyard is ill-omened.
لكن الاحتفاظ بالتابوت في الفناء نذير شؤم.
Let's skip the ceremony.
دعونا نتجاوز الحفل.
(Tang Yuzhu Second Concubine) Stop crying, it's so upsetting!
(المحظية الثانية لتانغ يوزو) توقفي عن البكاء، إنه أمر محزن للغاية!
Yuzhu,
يوتشو،
(Qin Ruoyi Third Concubine) we have waited two years for the General.
(المحظية الثالثة تشين رويي) لقد انتظرنا الجنرال لمدة عامين.
But who would have thought
لكن من كان ليظن ذلك؟
that the General would pass away?
هل سيموت الجنرال؟
Does that mean we must spend our lives
هل يعني ذلك أننا يجب أن نقضي حياتنا
being widows here in this manor?
هل سنكون أرامل هنا في هذا القصر؟
If he's gone, we should just leave.
إذا رحل، فعلينا أن نغادر فحسب.
The world is vast.
العالم واسع.
Surely it can hold two women.
بالتأكيد يمكنها استيعاب امرأتين.
But we are already wed.
لكننا متزوجان بالفعل.
Whether we stay or go
سواء بقينا أو رحلنا
is not for us to decide.
ليس من شأننا أن نقرر.
The General isn't dead.
الجنرال لم يمت.
What? What are you saying?
ماذا؟ ماذا تقول؟
Am I not allowed to hear this?
أليس من حقي سماع هذا؟
Yuzhu,
يوتشو،
the General is alive.
الجنرال على قيد الحياة.
He has returned.
لقد عاد.
He's still alive?
هل ما زال على قيد الحياة؟
The General is still alive.
لا يزال الجنرال على قيد الحياة.
If he's not dead, why are you still in tears?
إذا لم يكن ميتاً، فلماذا ما زلتِ تبكين؟
These are tears of joy.
هذه دموع الفرح.
Yet in my heart,
لكن في قلبي،
there's still a trace of resentment.
لا يزال هناك أثر من الاستياء.
Why so?
لماذا؟
Yuzhu, think about it.
يوزو، فكر في الأمر.
Today, Old Madam
اليوم، يا سيدتي العجوز
found the General a proper wife.
وجد للجنرال زوجة مناسبة.
Thought she was to be buried with him.
ظنت أنها ستدفن معه.
But the General returned at such a time.
لكن الجنرال عاد في ذلك الوقت.
So tonight
إذن الليلة
would become the couple's
سيصبح ملكًا للزوجين
wedding night?
ليلة الزفاف؟
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
We've waited two years for the General.
لقد انتظرنا الجنرال لمدة عامين.
Even the wedding night
حتى ليلة الزفاف
should follow the order.
ينبغي اتباع الترتيب.
But Lady Yanchu is the rightful wife.
لكن السيدة يانشو هي الزوجة الشرعية.
It's only fair she has precedence over us.
من العدل أن تكون لها الأسبقية علينا.
You're right, Yuzhu.
أنت على حق، يوتشو.
The ceremony is over.
انتهى الحفل.
Shall I leave now?
هل أغادر الآن؟
It's not over yet.
لم ينته الأمر بعد.
Tomorrow morning,
صباح الغد،
you must pay respects to Old Madam.
يجب عليك أن تُظهر الاحترام للسيدة العجوز.
General,
عام،
tonight is our wedding night.
الليلة هي ليلة زفافنا.
If you choose to leave,
إذا اخترت المغادرة،
how will I explain to Old Madam?
كيف سأشرح ذلك للسيدة العجوز؟
What do you propose?
ماذا تقترح؟
Let's make a deal.
لنعقد صفقة.
Tell me what it is.
أخبرني ما هو.
His Majesty values
جلالته يُقدّر
harmony within families above all.
الانسجام داخل الأسر هو الأهم على الإطلاق.
Filial piety first.
بر الوالدين أولاً.
That's why Old Madam
لهذا السبب يا سيدتي العجوز
endured so many misunderstandings
لقد تحملت الكثير من سوء الفهم
just to find you a proper wife,
فقط لأجد لك زوجة مناسبة،
to silence the gossip.
لإسكات النميمة.
But today, I noticed that
لكنني لاحظت اليوم أن
the rift between you and your mother ran deep.
كان الخلاف بينك وبين والدتك عميقاً.
I heard that when you were away,
سمعت ذلك عندما كنت مسافراً،
she married you two concubines.
لقد تزوجتكما من محظيتين.
Not much peace inside
لا يوجد الكثير من الهدوء في الداخل
this household, yes?
هذا المنزل، أليس كذلك؟
With the household in disarray,
مع فوضى المنزل،
if word reaches His Majesty,
إذا وصل الخبر إلى جلالته،
it surely won't bode well.
من المؤكد أن هذا لن يبشر بالخير.
Yuzhu,
يوتشو،
just now, Xiaocui told me,
أخبرتني شياوتسوي للتو،
Lady Yaochu stood in the Memorial Hall today,
وقفت السيدة ياوتشو اليوم في قاعة الذكرى،
and openly defied Old Madam.
وتحدى السيدة العجوز علنًا.
If she lies beside the General tonight,
إذا نامت بجانب الجنرال الليلة،
spinning tales about us,
يختلقون القصص عنا،
then uses her sly charms to win
ثم تستخدم سحرها الماكر للفوز
over the General's heart,
فوق قلب الجنرال،
you and I
أنت وأنا
will be stuck with such a foolish mistress,
سيبقى عالقاً مع عشيقة حمقاء كهذه،
and our days ahead will be hard.
وستكون أيامنا المقبلة صعبة.
What should we do now?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن؟
Yuzhu, wait a moment.
يوتشو، انتظر لحظة.
Something urgent just came up.
طرأ أمر عاجل.
You… Go and rest.
أنت... اذهب واسترح.
Have some snacks.
تناول بعض الوجبات الخفيفة.
I have something urgent to see to.
لدي أمر عاجل يجب عليّ القيام به.
Fool.
أحمق.
I'll soothe the household for you.
سأقوم بتهدئة المنزل من أجلك.
You protect the one at Guanyin Nunnery.
أنت تحمي الشخص الموجود في دير غوانيين.
Will that do?
هل هذا يكفي؟
Who exactly in the Guanyin Nunnery
من هم بالضبط في دير غوانيين؟
that you care so deeply about?
التي تهتم بها بشدة؟
She's my mother.
إنها أمي.
Alright then.
حسناً إذاً.
I'll think this over.
سأفكر في الأمر.
But don't stir any trouble again.
لكن لا تثير أي مشاكل مرة أخرى.
If you bear a child one day,
إذا أنجبتِ طفلاً يوماً ما،
I could even arrange for your mother
بل يمكنني حتى أن أرتب الأمر لوالدتك
to stay with you daily.
ليبقى معك يومياً.
General.
عام.
When it comes to having heirs,
عندما يتعلق الأمر بإنجاب الورثة،
my efforts alone won't change much.
جهودي وحدها لن تغير الكثير.
General, you must also give.
أيها الجنرال، يجب عليك أيضاً أن تعطي.
For a woman,
بالنسبة للمرأة،
your courage is remarkable.
شجاعتك رائعة.
And why is that a problem?
ولماذا تُعتبر هذه مشكلة؟
(If offering myself could make him protect my mother,)
(لو كان بإمكاني أن أعرض نفسي عليه أن يحمي أمي،)
(then why not?)
(فلماذا لا؟)
♪New snow falls thick beneath the eaves♪
♪يتساقط الثلج الجديد بكثافة تحت حواف السقف♪
♪Covering the courtyard gate♪
♪تغطية بوابة الفناء♪
♪Your gaze melts winter into spring♪
♪نظرتك تذيب الشتاء في الربيع♪
♪Turning back from the boundless multitude♪
♪العودة من بين الجموع التي لا حدود لها♪
♪Gazing at you in that fleeting moment♪
♪أنظر إليك في تلك اللحظة العابرة♪
♪All the hardships fade into drifting dust♪
♪تتلاشى كل المصاعب في غبار متناثر♪
♪A foolish dream turns earnest with you in it♪
♪حلمٌ ساذجٌ يتحول إلى حلمٍ جادٍّ بوجودك فيه♪
♪Even a feigned play can grow into true affection♪
♪حتى التمثيل المصطنع يمكن أن يتحول إلى عاطفة حقيقية♪
♪Too many dusks walked alone beneath my umbrella♪
♪كثير من الغسقات سارت وحيدة تحت مظلتي♪
♪Yet I crave the warmth left in your embrace♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى الدفء المتبقي في حضنك♪
♪Among thousands of bright lamps, is there one♪
♪من بين آلاف المصابيح الساطعة، هل يوجد واحد؟♪
♪That waits quietly for me?♪
♪هل ينتظرني بصمت؟♪
♪Time grinds through the rings of memory♪
♪ يمر الوقت سريعاً عبر حلقات الذاكرة ♪
♪Only you keep me warm in the long night♪
♪أنتِ وحدكِ من تُدفئينني في الليل الطويل♪
♪Scars left by the days gone by♪
♪ندوبٌ خلّفتها الأيام الخوالي♪
♪Lie upon the lines of our hands together♪
♪استلقوا على خطوط أيدينا معًا♪
♪I hold out a heart sincere and true♪
♪أُخرج قلباً صادقاً وحقيقياً♪
♪Crossing the deep courtyard♪
♪عبور الفناء العميق♪
♪Just to trade it for one kiss from you♪
♪فقط لأستبدلها بقبلة واحدة منك♪
♪Praying our hair turns gray without regret♪
♪ندعو أن يتحول شعرنا إلى اللون الرمادي دون ندم♪
♪So that true love will finally come to be♪
♪حتى يتحقق الحب الحقيقي في النهاية♪